Guide to the Frederic Spiegelberg Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers
  - Notes and Notebooks, 1917-1980; Series 4
    - Notebook: Yoga and surrealism, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Notebook: Assorted topics, 1941 and undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Notebooks: two, in German, 1922 and undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks: in German, [unlabelled] (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Notebook: miscellaneous in English, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Notes: miscellaneous 1956-58 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Notes: miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Writings, 1938-1953 and undated; Series 5
    - "A Child's Prayer at Bedtime" (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "The Christian-Theological Synthesis of Freedom and Security; IV Report on an Opinion Survey," Spiegelberg and Hedley, Pacific Coast Theological Group, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - essay on Aurobindo [typescript] (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - “Indian Analogies to Philosophy and Pyschology of Religion” (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Possible translation of Indian text (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Indische Psychophysik" (from Sonderbruck Aus: Ursprung und Gegenwart des integralen Bewußtseins), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts (English) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - The Religion of Non-Religion, being a lecture by Friedrich Spiegelberg. London: The Buddhist Lodge, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Das religiöse Erleben bei Plotin" [typescript] (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - “Shadow of the Soul” [prepared for Stanford class] (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - “Spiritual Vocabulary” (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - "Die Stellung Luthers zur Heiligen Schrift nach den Vorreden zu den einzelnen biblischen Büchern. [typescript] (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Abstract of paper on The Suksma sarira in Indian Psycho-physiology (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - “Tibet Block Prints” (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - “What a New American Expects of the Society of Friends” [incomplete] (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Family Papers, 1916-1986; Series 6
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German) 1937-1946 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German) 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German), author unknown but similar typewriter text, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German), author unkown but on same paper 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German) 1950-59 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German) 1964-1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in German) undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Garraux, Dora, to Mrs. Spiegelberg (in German) with 1 page of text on dance, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg from E. Ziegler (in German) 1938-1950 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg (in English) 1937, 1953-1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Letters to Rosli Spiegelberg from M. J. van Lobel Sels 1953-1985 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Frederic Spiegelberg (in German), many from Helene Spiegelberg 1940-1949 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Letters to Frederic Spiegelberg (in German) from Eva Spiegelberg 1971 and undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Letters from Muhlemann family (in German) 1942-1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Letters to family (Dr. & Mrs. Spiegelberg and Corinne, in German) 1946-1991 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Letter fragments (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Letters (in German), copied 1943 and 1986 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Envelopes, German (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Postcards 1936-1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Spiegelberg, Valentin, correspondence (mostly in German), 1957, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Wilkinson, Corinne Spiegelberg, correspondence 1949-1964 and undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Wilkinson, Corinne Spiegelberg, wedding 1963 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Wilkinson, Corinne Spiegelberg, miscellaneous papers 1956-1986 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Rosli Spiegelberg dance class announcement, New York circa 1940 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Will of FS’s brother, typed with no signature (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Will of Eva Emma Spiegelberg, with German court document 1969 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Unsorted holiday and greeting cards (Box 14)
    - Spiegelberg family history: German documents and letters, 1916-1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - German documents 1960-1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - United States documents (tax return, lease, Selective Service, WWII ration cards, and others), 1938-1960 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Spiegelberg: U. S. passports (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Travel, London 1937 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Travel, Europe, 1965-1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Travel, Europe 1978 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Financial documents, 1937-1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Financial documents, 1950-1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1941-1971 and undated; Series 7
    - Photos: Frederick Spiegelberg (one portrait, rest candid), 1971 and undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Photos: Corinne Spiegelberg Wilkinson, 1956-67 and undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Photos: family, 1941-61 and undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Photo: Steiner, Rudolf (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Photos: India (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Photos: Rome (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Photos, misc. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Photos, misc. (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Additional Papers, 1930s-1981; Accession ARCH-2011-184
  - Date books, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Date books, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Date books, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Date books, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Date books, 1970s-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Passport, travel notebook, and bank books, 1970s-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)